<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>AzDevOps on David Triana</title><link>https://davidtriana.com/tags/azdevops/</link><description>Recent content in AzDevOps on David Triana</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://davidtriana.com/tags/azdevops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Deploying Log4Brains ADRs in Azure Static Sites</title><link>https://davidtriana.com/posts/2021/deploying-log4brains-adr-in-azure-static-sites/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidtriana.com/posts/2021/deploying-log4brains-adr-in-azure-static-sites/</guid><description>Scenario Suppose your project has decided to use Log4Brains to record architectural decisions and now you need to make the resulting website available, in Microsoft Azure, via a CD Pipeline. To learn about ADRs or architectural decision records I highly recommend Steve Smith&amp;rsquo;s post about it.
Install Log4Brains and create your ADRs Install Log4Brains&amp;rsquo;s prerequisites to which I will add VsCode, with the .md extension Install Log4Brains and follow the getting started guide.</description></item><item><title>Updating Azure DevOps WorktItems programmatically</title><link>https://davidtriana.com/posts/2020/updating-azdevops-workitems-programmatically/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidtriana.com/posts/2020/updating-azdevops-workitems-programmatically/</guid><description>Scenario Some workitems are missing important information, the information was provided via an Excel sheet, the workitems need to be updated with this information without changing any other properties, particularly the workitem state.
Restrictions The workitems are in done state, and the process template has rules that prevent changes to the properties that need to be updated.
The Excel integration, which might be a solution, is not working on this environment because of a permissions error.</description></item><item><title>Migrating from local TFS to TFSPreview</title><link>https://davidtriana.com/posts/2012/migrating-from-local-tfs-to-tfspreview/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2012 23:11:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidtriana.com/posts/2012/migrating-from-local-tfs-to-tfspreview/</guid><description>TFSPreview, the Team Foundation on the cloud offered by Microsoft is a very good alternative, specially for distributed development teams.
It’s currently free and invite only but the invite codes are relatively easy to get. I asked for one in the page and got it in two days.
www.tfspreview.com
Account activated, TFS available but what about my existing projects in my local TFS?,
The official word is that there’s no supported way to migrate, but, there’re some reports of success using the TFS Integration tools, well, I’m about to confirm or deny that reports!</description></item></channel></rss>