<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on David Triana</title>
    <link>https://davidtriana.com/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on David Triana</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://davidtriana.com/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Visual Studio Code Remote</title>
      <link>https://davidtriana.com/posts/2020/vscode-remote/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidtriana.com/posts/2020/vscode-remote/</guid>
      <description>Visual Studio Code Remote enables scenarios where the editing happens on the client machine, but all the processing, build and dependencies happen somewhere else.
This is great for situations where the software being build requieres some specific setup that conflicts with your current machine or operating system, or to provide isolation between different projects or development environments, or to have access to more performant hardware or better internet connection, for the build, pulling dependencies, pushing containers, pulling docker images and many other scenarios where your local machine is not ideal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting the Shell back on WSL</title>
      <link>https://davidtriana.com/posts/2020/getting-the-shell-back-on-wsl/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidtriana.com/posts/2020/getting-the-shell-back-on-wsl/</guid>
      <description>I have been using Linux more and more, via WSL, and learning a lot along the way.
Part of the jorney is breaking and fixing things, which is exactly what happened to me today.
I was trying to get the very nice command prompt, like the one from Scott Hanselman, and at some point following different steps from the ones shared by Scott I installed zsh as my shell.
After trying the zsh approach and not being able to make it work, I decided to revert, and stick to what Scott did, so first thing was removing zsh,</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
