<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>IIS on David Triana</title><link>https://davidtriana.com/tags/iis/</link><description>Recent content in IIS on David Triana</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>david@davidtriana.com (David Triana)</managingEditor><webMaster>david@davidtriana.com (David Triana)</webMaster><copyright>2022 David Triana All rights reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2011 19:25:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://davidtriana.com/tags/iis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Missing management server delegation, 401 error and 403.14 error when deploying a new IIS7.5 for Web Deploy and ASP.NET MVC 2/3</title><link>https://davidtriana.com/posts/2011/missing-management-server-delegation-401-error-and-403-14-error-when-deploying-a-new-iis7-5-for-web-deploy-and-asp-net-mvc-23/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2011 19:25:00 +0000</pubDate><author>david@davidtriana.com (David Triana)</author><guid>https://davidtriana.com/posts/2011/missing-management-server-delegation-401-error-and-403-14-error-when-deploying-a-new-iis7-5-for-web-deploy-and-asp-net-mvc-23/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last night I was setting up a new box for a web site migration and lost a lot of time with that 3 issues.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I used Web Platform Installer to setup most of the server hoping that it will leave everything working as expected, however I found that is not the case.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First I needed to setup the Web Deploy service to install the web application from visual studio, however the Web Platform Installer leaves a few things missing when it deals with the Web Deploy.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="missing-management-server-delegation-icon">Missing Management Server Delegation icon&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The first problem I found is that when following the instructions to setup the web deploy service &lt;a href="http://learn.iis.net/page.aspx/516/configure-the-web-deployment-handler/">http://learn.iis.net/page.aspx/516/configure-the-web-deployment-handler/&lt;/a> , in the Part 2, there must be a Management Service Delegation icon, however it wasn’t present in my box. After trying the add role features and looking around in the forums I found out that the setup from WPI fail to install that component.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Solution&lt;/strong>: Download the setup, choose add features and select all, or uninstall and reinstall selecting complete.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="401-error-when-deploying-from-visual-studio">401 error when deploying from Visual Studio&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>After finishing the setup procedure for Web Deploy I tried to setup the application from visual studio, however I keep getting http 401 errors. This time the forums didn’t helped. All the posts are related to not following the instructions for the web deploy setup but I even repeat the process from the start and no luck.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It turns out that the client machine was using web deploy 1.0 while the server was with the 2.0 version. Updated the client with WPI and voila.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="40314-error-when-accessing-the-mvc-application">403.14 error when accessing the MVC application&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Finally the application deployed from Visual Studio, everything seems fine but the application gives a http 403.14 error. Again the forums offer little help suggesting reinstalling the static content compression feature and things like that, however at the third page of results in BING I found the solution:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>C:\Windows\Microsoft.NET\Framework64\v4.0.30319\aspnet_regiis -i&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>