<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Certifications on David Triana</title><link>https://davidtriana.com/tags/certifications/</link><description>Recent content in Certifications on David Triana</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>david@davidtriana.com (David Triana)</managingEditor><webMaster>david@davidtriana.com (David Triana)</webMaster><copyright>2022 David Triana All rights reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://davidtriana.com/tags/certifications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Renewing Microsoft Certifications</title><link>https://davidtriana.com/posts/2021/renewing-microsoft-certifications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>david@davidtriana.com (David Triana)</author><guid>https://davidtriana.com/posts/2021/renewing-microsoft-certifications/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="action-required---your-microsoft-certification-will-expire-in-180-days">Action required - Your Microsoft Certification will expire in 180 days!&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>That email subject, from May 21, asked for action, to get one of my certifications renewed, or &amp;ldquo;If your certification expires, you must earn the certification again by passing the required certification exam(s)&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This renewal process is &lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/learn/certifications/renew-your-microsoft-certification">new in many ways&lt;/a>, main differences are&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The topics covered are not necessarily the same as for the original exam/certification&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The exam itself is simpler than the proctored exam, no proctor, no dedicated exam app&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>I renewed 3 certifications with this process,&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/learn/certifications/azure-developer/renew/">Azure Developer Associate&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/learn/certifications/devops-engineer/renew/">DevOps Engineer Expert&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/learn/certifications/azure-solutions-architect/renew/">Azure Solutions Architect Expert&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>I passed all on the first try, however the renewal exams can be repeated as many times as needed&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://davidtriana.com/images/posts/2021/exams.png" alt="&amp;ldquo;Exams&amp;rdquo;" title="Exams">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To prepare, I went through all the linked materials on each of the certification pages, all of which go to the Microsoft Learn site, and include theory, labs and exam. I highly recommend this approach because&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The liked materials are directly related to the questions in the renewal exam&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The Microsoft Learn materials and labs are very well made, up to date and relevant&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>During the renewal exam, without a proctor or dedicated app, nothing prevents you from navigating back to the learning materials or searching for the answers online. While this approach might work to renew the certification, I think that misses the point. I think going through the materials preparing for the exam, and then consciously answering the exam questions fulfills the &amp;ldquo;brush up on your skills&amp;rdquo; objective in the invitation email.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>About the individual exams, what I found is that all the topics are covered in the learning materials and a lot of the topics from the original exams are not part of the renewal. The questions are less &amp;ldquo;tricky&amp;rdquo; than in the proctored exams and all the questions are multiple selections, no labs, no &amp;ldquo;order the commands&amp;rdquo; or any other of the question types available in the proctored exams.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="see-more">See More&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Something that happened to me while preparing for the DevOps exam, opening the links to the learning materials, is that I missed some of the materials. While doing the exam I got some questions for which I wasn&amp;rsquo;t prepared, then after the exam I went back to the page and noticed the &amp;ldquo;See More&amp;rdquo; link at the bottom of the list of training materials, same link is present in the Architect Expert exam, and I learned my lesson.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="celebrate">Celebrate&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://davidtriana.com/images/posts/2021/celebrate.png" alt="&amp;ldquo;Celebrate&amp;rdquo;" title="Celebrate">&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>